The Life of Muhammadﷺ, Madinan Period, Volume 2
By Imam Anwar Al_Awlaki;
اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۝بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۝
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد
وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
اَلسَّلَامُ عَلَيْكُمْ وَرَحْمةُ الله وَبَرَكَاتُه’
Rasool Allah ﷺ had a dream,
he saw that he was making Tawaf(طواف) around Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) along with the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم
and then they shaved their heads and some of them shorten their hair after that.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ now, it has been six years since he has left Makkah along with the Muhajireen رضي الله عنهم
and they dearly missed, Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه),
Makkah the greatest of the land of Allahعَزّوجَلّ it was beloved to them
because of the religious reasons and also because it was their home.
So, they were longing to go back to Makkah and visit Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)
and as one of Mufassireen(مفسرين) said: Commenting on the Ayah(آية).
وَإِذْ جَعَلْنَا الْبَيْتَ مَثَابَةً لِلنَّاسِ
We have made the house of Allah Masabah(مَثَابَةْ)
Masabah(مَثَابَةْ) means a place that you want to return to, all the time.
And this Mufassir(مفسر) gave the example
he said, that the young camel whenever, it would go away, to play
it would always want to come back to its mother
just to see the mother and touch the mother and then it would go and play again,
just to feel the comfort that the mother is still there.
And he gave this analogy to the believer and Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
The believer whenever he see's Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) the first time
whenever, he goes around at the first time, he's hooked for life.
And he would always want to return back again and again to visit it
and even though he might be a foreigner in Makkah but he feels at home.
Even though, it's not his home he might not speak the language
but he feels at home, as soon as he enters into Al-Haram(اَلْحَرم).
And Rasool Allah ﷺ has called on, invited the Muslims of Madina
and the surrounding areas the tribes that have become Muslim around Al-Madina(اَلْمدينة),
he invited them all to come out with him for Umrah(عمرة)
and the ones who responded to his call numbered around fourteen hundred, a sizable number
and they set out on the path towards Makkah.
When they reach to Dhul-Khaleefah(ذوالخليفه),
which is the Meeqaat(ميقات) of Ahlul-Madina(اهل المدينه) that's a place where they start their Ehraam(إحرام).
Rasool Allah ﷺ he told the Muslims to put on their garments of Ehraam(إحرام)
and to mark the sacrificial animals,
which was the tradition that the animals that are set for sacrifice are marked
and Rasool Allah ﷺ had with him 70 camels
and they started making Talbih(تلبيح)
لَبَّيْكْ اَلَّلهُمَّ لَبَّيْكْ
The procession was peaceful.
Rasool Allah ﷺ intended, no fighting
and therefore he did not take with him any arms
except for the swords in their sheaths and an Arab man would never travel without his sword
but this was not an army set out to fight,
this was an army going out for the Ibadah(عبادة), the ritual of Umrah(عمرة).
However, Rasool Allah ﷺ even though this was his intention
but Rasool Allah ﷺ was very careful, very alert and he would not be taken by surprise
and therefore, he had 20 men on horse, horseback ahead of him
as a protection and also to clear the route
and check, if there's any dangers on the way.
And he also sent a spy for reconnaissance to gather information for him
and the man responsible for this mission was Bishar Ibn Sufiyan(بشرإبن سفيان),
while the man who was appointed over the horsemen was Abbad Bin Bishr رضي الله عنه.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was a very alert man, very careful,
he was a man known to attend to the details
and as he said about himself.
لَسْتُ بِالْخِبِّ وَلا الخِب يَخْدَعْنِيْ
I am not a trickster, but the trickster cannot trick me.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه could not be taken by surprise and could not be tricked
and everybody knew that about him
and that's reflected through his words, and statements, and the advice, that he would give Rasool Allah ﷺ
as we can see throughout the Seerah(سيرة) of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) told him;
يا رسول الله تَدْخُلُ عَلى قَوْمٍ هُمْ لَكَ الْحَرْبْ بِغَيْرِ سلاح و لا قراع
O Messenger of Allah, are you going to enter on a people, who are in the state of war with you, without any weapons?
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ agreed with Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) and he called the weapons from Madina
but they were to be separate from the group, which Rasool Allah ﷺ and the Sahabah(صحابه), it would be separate.
They would have their weapon separate because
they wanted everybody to see that they have came for peaceful mission, tayyeb(طيب).
Now, the man sent on reconnaissance he came back, this man Bishr Bin Sufiaan(بِشربن سفيان), he came back to Rasool Allah ﷺ
and told him that Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) has actually marched out and they're preparing for war.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
اَشِيْرُوْا عَلَيَّ اَيُّهَاالنَّاسْ اَتَرَوْنَا
اَنْ اَمِيْلَ اِلَى عِيَالِهِمْ وَذراري هؤلاء الَّذِيْنَ يُرِيْدُوْنَ اِنْ يَّصُدُّوْنَا عَنِّ الْبَيْتْ
Men give me your advice,
Do you think that I should head for the children and families of those, who wished to keep us from Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).?
You see, brothers and sisters
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) held a very high status in Arabia among the Arab tribes.
That is because they were custodians of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)
but it was a known tradition, it was known common knowledge among the people
that no one should prevent, anyone from Hajj(حَجْ) and Umrah(عمرة).
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) are now trying to prevent Muhammadﷺ and the Muslims from entering Makkah
and this is unheard of, it is something that you don't do.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ is asking the companions
should we head for the children and families of those,
who are those?
Rasool Allah ﷺ is here talking about the tribes, who allied themselves with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
in this horrible mission of preventing the Muslims from entering into Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)
because Bishr(بشر), when it came to Rasool Allah ﷺ, he said;
اِنَّ قُرَيْشً قَدْ جَمْعُوْ لَكَ جَمْعًا وَجَمْعُوْ لَكَ الْاَحَابِيْشْ
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) have mobilized themselves, and they have also mobilized Al-Ahabeish(ألأحابيش),
Al-Ahabeish(ألأحابيش) is the confederation of tribes
three or more tribes that have allied themselves with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and Rasool Allah ﷺ was saying;
How about we attack the families and children of these other tribes?
So, that they would have to come back and protect their families
while then we could move on towards Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
تَكُوْنُ عُنُقًا قَدْ قَطَاحَ الله
So, by this we would break the alliance and split up their army
Abu Bakr رضي الله عنه he answered, he gave his opinion, he said;
يا رسول الله خَرَجْتَ عَامِدً لِّهَذَالْبَيْتْ
لَا تريد قَتْلَ اَحَدٍ وَلَا حَرْبَ اَحَدْ فَتَوَجَّه لَهْ فَمَنْ صدَّنَا عنه قَاتَلْنَاه
Messenger of Allah, you have come forth to visit Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)
not intending to do battle or to make war against anyone.
Proceed to it, and we will fight anybody who blocks our way.
This was the opinion Abu-Bakr Siddique رضي الله عنه and Rasool Allah ﷺ agreed with him
and therefore the plans of attacking these Kuffar(كفار) in their residence were stopped.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
اُمضُوْا عَلَى بَرَكَة الله
then proceed onwards in Allah's name.
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) have sent a force of 200 men led by Khalid Ibn Waleed رضي الله عنه and Ikrimah Bin Abi Jahel(عِكرِمَة بن ابي جهل).
When Rasool Allah ﷺ received that piece of information he announced to his army and said;
Who will take us on a path that will take us around them
so a man from Aslam(أسلم), he offered to guide them through a back road
so to speak, it was very rough difficult terrain
but eventually they made it, to the plain of Al-Hudaybiyya(ألْحُدَيْبِيَةْ)
which is to the south of Makkah and it was only a days walk from the holy city.
When Khalid Ibn Walid(خالد ابن وليد) received this information that the Muslims have went around him
and then he rushed back, towards Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and now Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) knew that Rasool Allah ﷺ is only days distance from them.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ reached to Al-Hudaybiyya(ألْحُدَيْبِيَةْ)
his camel Al-Qaswaa(اَلْقَصْوَاء), the famous camel of Rasool Allah ﷺ
which we have talked about in our earlier session.
Al-Qaswaa(اَلْقَصْوَاء) sat down, and when they would tell her; Hal(هل), Hal(هل)
which is the word that they would use to ask the camel to stand up and move the camel refused,
the camel refused to stand up.
So, they said;
خَلَاَتِ الْقَصْوَاء
Al-Qaswaa(اَلْقَصْوَاء) has become refractory.
With these animals, camels, horses donkeys, the animals that are used for transportation,
sometimes they become obstinate and they suddenly refuse to take orders.
So, the people  were saying;
خَلَتِ الْقَصْوَاء
it has become refractory.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
وَمَا خَلَتِ الْقَصْوَاءْ وَمَا هُوَ (ذَاكَ)لَهَا بِخُلُقْ
Al-Qaswaa(اَلْقَصْوَاء) has not, and that is not in her nature.
وَلَكِنْ حَبَسَهَا حَابِسُ الْفِيْلْ
But she has been held back by Him, Who held back to the elephant.
You remember the story of the elephant,
Abraha(اَبْرَاهَةْ), and his army when they were attacking Makkah, the elephant refused to proceed.
But when they would turn the elephant around, it would suddenly run away,
they would turn it back to Makkah, and it would refuse to move.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
The One, Who has held back the elephant is the One, Who held back the camel.
But there's a big difference here, then it was Abraha(اَبْرَاهَةْ) and the kuffar(كفار)
and now, it is Rasool Allah ﷺ and the Sahabah(صحابه).
So, what does this mean?
Ibn Hajar(اِبْن حجَر) comments on this and says;
Allahعَزّوجَلّ knew then and now that the people of Makkah are going to become Muslim
and therefore, he prevented bloodshed then, and now.
Then, it was by destroying the army of Abraha(اَبْرَاهَةْ) and his followers
and now, it is by opening up the doors to peace
and if Rasool Allah ﷺ had proceeded onward
and war would had ensued,
there would have been a lot of bloodshed.
But Allahسبحانه وتعالى, held back the Muslims and they stopped
when Al-Qaswaa(اَلْقَصْوَاء) has refused to move.
Eventually, it did move, but this event, Rasool Allah ﷺ turned our attention to it,
that it is something done by Allahعَزّوجَلّ
and this was the explanation given by Ibn Hajar رَحِمَهُ الله.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: By Him, Who holds my soul in His hand,
I'll accept any request that, they make of me
by which the sanctuaries of Allah are dignified
and in another narration,
in which the ties of family are honored.
Rasool Allah ﷺ had announced and made it clear
that he intends on peace and he will accept any offer that they make
as long as the commands of Allah are  honored.
There was a well in Hudaybiyya(حُدَيْبِيَّةْ)
but when the Sahabah(صحابه) went to drink from the well, it was empty.
So, they came to Rasool Allah ﷺ, to tell him about it
Rasool Allah ﷺ, he gave him an arrow from his quiver
and told them to take it, and drop it into the well and they did so.
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) water started coming out from this well.
There are many miracles of similar sort, that happened to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Skirmishes would happen
and prisoners were taken by Rasool Allah ﷺ from the Mushrikeen(مشركين) but no one was killed.
One example was narrated by Salamah Ibn Aqwa رضي الله عنه
He said: I was sleeping under a tree
and there were some Mushrikeen(مشركين) lying down under an adjacent tree.
And they were speaking against Rasool Allah ﷺ
so I went to sleep under a tree, in the distance.
I didn't want to hear the rubbish that, they were talking about.
Then I heard the call to arms something has happened.
So, there was a call of Al-Muhajireen(ألمهاجرين)
and Salamah(سلمه) said: So, I rushed towards these four Mushrikeen(مشركين), who were sleeping under this tree
and they had their swords hanging on the branches of this tree.
So, I gathered all of their swords and had them, under my arm
and I had my sword in my arm and I told them if any one of you makes any move I'm gonna chop off his head
and I took them as prisoners to Rasool Allah ﷺ, four of them.
So, there were events of this sort.
The situation was very delicate
Rasool Allah ﷺ wanted to send an envoy into Makkah,
to explain to them that we have not come with the intention of fighting,
we have come to make Tawaf(طواف) around Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
Rasool Allah ﷺ chose Kharaash Ibn Umayyah(خراش بن إمية)
who's from the tribe of Khuza'a(خزاعة),
Kharash(خراش) went into Makkah, how did they deal with him?
They kill his camel and they almost killed him
until, the Ahabeesh(أحابيش) interfered and protected him.
So, this is how they dealt with the envoy of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
You can see throughout the story that Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were in a state of despair
they were confused, they were desperate, and they were frustrated.
They were people who are arrogant and now they were humiliated.
They were losing their position in Arabia
and their pride was preventing them from seeing clearly.
So, you see a lot of frustration in the way they were behaving
Kharaash Ibn Umayyah(خراش بن إمية) is coming to announce to them
first of all he's a messenger and messengers are not killed
and second of all, he's coming to tell them that we have not come for the purpose of fighting
and this is how they dealt with him, so he left.
Rasool Allah ﷺ wanted to send someone else
so he summoned Umar Bin Khattab رضي الله عنه
and he told him, his intentions.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) he responded back and said;
There is none of my family Bannu Udae(بنوعدي)
who's left in Makkah to give me a protection, and Quraish(قريش);
وَقَدْ عَلِمَتْ قُرَيْش عَدَاوَتِي لَهَا
And Quraish(قريش) they know very well, my animosity towards them.
But if you insist on me going, then I will go.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) gave a frank assessment of the situation
that he believes that he would be in danger, if he goes into Makkah
but if it's an order then he will obey.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was silent, so then Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) suggested another name.
He said: But how about you send Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) because his clan are there.
Now, Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) belongs to Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه)
and Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه) are from the major branch of Quraish(قريش)
Bannu Abd-Manaf(بنوعبدالمناف) there were two families in Quraish(قريش)
that held the reins of leadership in the town
and these were Bannu Makhzoom(بنومخذوم) and Bannu Abd-Manaf(بنوعبدالمناف)
Bannu Makhzoom(بنومخذوم) among the famous personalities of Bannu Makhzoom(بنومخذوم) are;
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل), who was the head of Quraish(قريش) until, his death.
And he was the leader in the fight against the Muslims.
And then you have Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(إلوليد إبن مغيرة) and Khalid Ibn Walid(خالد ابن وليد) his son,
these belong to the clan of Bannu Makhzoom(بنومخذوم).
And then you have Bannu Abd-Manaf(بنوعبدالمناف)
and the two major branches of Bannu Abd-Manaf(بنوعبدالمناف) are;
Bannu Hashim(بنوهاشم), the family of Rasool Allah ﷺ and Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه).
So Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه), by the way are very close relatives of Bannu Hashim(بنوهاشم).
Now, Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) belong to Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه).
So, when Rasool Allah ﷺ sent him to Makkah,
he was immediately, given protection by the major figure of Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه) after Abu Sufiyan(ابوسُفيان),
see Abu Sufiyan(ابوسُفيان) also belongs to Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّه) but he wasn't there at the time.
So, the one who gave protection to Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was his cousin Abbaan Bin Saeed Bin Al-Aas(عَبَّان بن سَعِيد بن اَلْعَاص).
He had him ride with him on his camel and he went in front of Quraish(قريش) and said;
This man is under my protection.
Who would dare now to touch Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان),
when he entered in the protection of Abbaan Bin Saeed Bin Al-Aas(عَبَّان بن سَعِيد بن اَلْعَاص).
The mission of Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was two fold.
Number one: He would announce to Quraish(قريش) that the Muslims have not come for war.
Number two: He was told by Rasool Allah ﷺ to visit the believing men and believing women
and give them the glad tidings that Islam will be victorious that the Muslims will win.
Uthman Ibn Affan رضي الله عنه he went to the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and told them.
بَعَثَنِيْ رَسُولِ اللهِ صلى الله عليه وسلم لِيَدْعُوْكُمْ اِلَى الاِسْلَامْ
وَاِلَى اللهِ جَلَّ ثَنَاءُ وَتَدْخُلُوْنَ فِيْ الدِّيْنِ كَآفَّهْ
فَاِنَّ الله مُظْهِرُ دِيْنِهِ وَ مُعِزْ نَبِيِّهِ
Rasool Allah ﷺ sent me to you to call you to Islam and to Allah
and that you enter in the religion of Allah
because Allah will give victory to His religion and will honor His Prophet.
وَاُخْرَى تُكْفَوْنَ وَيَكُوْنُ الَّذِيْ يَلِّيْ هَذَالْاَمْرْ مِنْه غَيْرُكُمْ
فَاِنْ ظفِرَ بِرَسُوْلَ اللهِ صلى الله عليه وَسلم فَذَالِكَ مَا اَرَدْتُّمْ
وَاِنْ ظفَرَ كُنْتُمْ بِالخِيَّارْ
بَيْنَ اَنْ تَدْخُلُوْ فِيْمَا دَخَلَ فِيهِالنَّاسْ
اَوْ تُقَاتِلُوْ وَاَنْتُمْ وَافِرُوْنَ جَامُوْنْ
اِنَّ الْحَرْبَ قَدْ نَهِكَتْكُمْ وَاَذْهَبَتِ الْاَمَاثِلَ مِنْكُمْ
And then he told them: And let someone else take care of this affair.
So, if they defeat the Messenger of Allah, then that is what you are asking for
and if he wins then you have the option of either following what the rest of the people have followed
or you fight and you have taken some rest
because war has exhausted you, and the best among you have been killed.
Very direct and blunt message telling them that you're exhausted,
he's telling them in their faces that, you are exhausted
you are tired, you cannot carry on this fight forever.
You see, they have been worn out.
Then he said;
وَاُخْرَى اِنَّ رَسُوْلَ الله صلى الله عليه وَسلم يُخْبِرُكُمْ
اَنَّه’لَمْ يَأت لِقِتَالِ اَحَدْ اِنَّمَا جَآءَ مُعْتَمِرًا
معه الْهَدْي عَلَيْهِ الْقَلَائِدْ يَنْحرْه’ وَيَنْصَرِفْ
Rasool Allah ﷺ telling you, he is informing you
that we have not came here to fight anyone
but we have come for Umrah(عمرة) with us the sacrificial animals marked,
we will slaughter them and leave.
Abbaan Bin Saeed(عَبَّان بِن سَعيد) told Usman Bin Affan رضي الله عنه;
If you want to make Tawaf(طواف) go ahead, no one can prevent you.
What did Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) do?
Actually some of the companions they were saying;
Uthman(عثمان) is lucky, now is making Tawaf(طواف).
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ heard them and said;
My expectation of him, is that, if he stays so and so years,
he would not make Tawaf(طواف) until, I make Tawaf(طواف)
and that was the case Uthman Bin Affan رضي الله عنه said;
مَا كُنْتُ لِأطُوْفَ بِالْبَيْتِ حَتَّى يَطُوْفَ بِهِ رسول الله
I wouldn't have made Tawaf(طواف) around the house of Allah,
until Rasool Allah ﷺ makes Tawaf(طواف) himself,
out of respect to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Quraish(قريش) were also sending envoys the first they sent was Budail Bin Warqaa(بديل بن ورقاء).
Budail Bin Warqaa(بديل بن ورقاء) came to Rasool Allah ﷺ
and he belong to the tribe of Khuza'a(خزاعة) and he came along with some men from Khuza'a(خزاعة).
As the books say,
كَانُوْا عَيْبَة نُصْحِ لِرسُولِ صلى الله عليه وسلم
They were trust worthy advisors of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
مُشرِكْهِمْ وَكَافِرْهِمْ
The disbelievers among them and the Muslims among them,
were very sympathetic to the Muslims.
And they were advisors of Rasool Allah ﷺ
and it says in one narration that anything that goes on in Makkah
the people of Khuza'a(خزاعة) would report it to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Rasool Allah ﷺ had information from within
and the ones, who are bringing the information to Rasool Allah ﷺ were both Muslim and non Muslim.
This was sort of like a tribal Alliance,
because Khuza'a(خزاعة) were allies of Bannu Hashim(بنوهاشم) in the time of Jahilliyah(جاهلية).
And since, the leader of Bannu Hashim(بنوهاشم) now, is Rasool Allah ﷺ
he is the most prominent figure among them.
Khuza'a(خزاعة) carried on this alliance, even though many of them were Mushrikeen(مشركين),
but they still considered themselves to be close to Bannu Hashim(بنوهاشم) and close to the Muslims.
And this shows you the situation that existed then
and there could be a lot of insight in this story.
And in the relations between the clans and tribes that existed then
and how Rasool Allah ﷺ was successful in his war.
And one can also see that part of that success is
because of his information gathering procedure
always Rasool Allah ﷺ, had spies roaming Arabia to gather information for him
and here we have insiders from within Makkah.
Because Khuza'a(خزاعة) were living in the outskirts of Makkah, very close to Makkah
and they would report to him whatever, was going on in the camp of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
So, Budail Bin Warqaa(بديل بن ورقاء) was first envoy sent, to meet with Rasool Allah ﷺ
He came to Muhammadﷺ and told him that Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
مَعَهُمُ الْعُوْذ اَلْمَطافِيْلْ قَدْ نَزَّلُّ وعَدَدَ مَا اَلْحُدَيْبِيَه
That Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) have came out, with them the camels with milk
meaning that they have came out with provisions
with the intention of staying for a long time,
if the circumstances demand so
and he told them they have.
وَلَبِسُوْا جُلُوْدً النَّمُوْرَ،
They have put on tiger skin and they're ready for war.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
لَمْ نَجْيء لقِتَالِ اَحَدْ
We did not come to fight anyone, we have come to make Umrah(عمرة).
يَا وَيْحَ قُرَيْشٍ لَقَدْ اَنهِكتَهُمُ الْحَرْبَ
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) have been consumed by warfare.
It has ruined them.
If they want, I will give them respite for a while.
They should then give me access to the people,
if I prevail and they wish to join into what the people have entered, they could do so.
Otherwise, they will have rested
if they refuse this, then I swear by Him, Who holds my soul in His hand,
I will battle them in this cause of mine until, I perish and Allah's will, will be done.
Rasool Allah ﷺ is telling Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) you have the option of either leaving me alone
or fighting me, and if you choose to fight me, I will win
and Allah's religion will prevail
and I'm not going to give up, I'm never going to give up, even if I perish.
So, he is making it clear to them, that I'm not going to give up
and Rasool Allah ﷺ is telling them that you have been exhausted by war.
And we talked about earlier, Rasool Allah ﷺ said, after the battle of Khandaq(خندق),
اَلْآنَ نَغْزُوهُمْ وَلاَ يَغْزُونَنَا
We wil from now on conquer them and they will not conquer us.
And that is what happened, Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) now are on the defensive.
They have no ability to wage an offensive battle against Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Budail Bin Warqaa(بديل بن ورقاء) told Rasool Ullah I'm going to tell them,
I'm going to convey to them, this message
Budail Bin Warqaa(بديل بن ورقاء) went back to Makkah
and the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) said;
He wants you to ask him, what happened, ignore him.
So, Budail(بديل) came in and he's waiting for someone to ask him
what happened and they were all quiet, so he told them;
He told them: Do you want me to tell you what happened.
Ikrimah Bin Abi Jahal(عِكْرِمَة بن ابي جهل) said: We don't want to hear anything from you.
They knew his sympathy towards the Muslims.
But then Safwaan Ibn Umayyah(صفوان اِبن أمَيَّة) and some others, they said;
Go ahead and tell us what happened.
He convey to them the message of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
They didn't like what they heard.
So, now they sent in, another man.
This time they sent, a man called Mikraz Bin Hafz(مكرزبن حفص).
When Rasool Allah ﷺ saw him. He said;
اِنَّ هَذَا رَجُلٌ غَادِر
This is a man of the betrayal
and why did Rasool Allah ﷺ say that about him?
Rasool Allah knew his nature.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) after that he led a force of 40 or 50 men from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
with the intention of circling around the Muslim camp,
trying to find any loner to take as prisoner.
They wanted to find anybody who would deviate away from the army
and they would capture him and take him back to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
What happened is the other way around.
It was the Muslims, who took them as prisoners, all of them, except Mikraz(مِكْرَز) who ran away.
They came in, to take prisoners and they were taken prisoners themselves.
Rasool Allah ﷺ because he came out, with the intension of peace
he released them all, with no condition.
Then Al-Hulais Bin Alqama(اَلْحُلَيْس بن عَلْقَمَة), the head of Al-Ahabeesh(اَلْاَحَابِيْش),
these are the Allies of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
He offered to go and meet with Rasool Allah ﷺ
when Rasool Allah ﷺ saw him, he said: This is a man from people who are devout
drive out the animals of sacrifice in front of him so he will see them.
So, the Muslims all what they had to do is,
to show out their intentions of Umrah(عمرة) publicly
and this man as soon as he saw that
he walked away without even meeting with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
He was so moved, by what he saw
he went back to the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and said;
All glory belongs to Allah,
it is not right for these people to be kept from Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)
and this is a Mushrik(مشرك) a Kafir(كافر).
But he saw it, is against the tradition, against the acceptable norms, of the time
to prevent people who came out for Umrah(عمرة) to prevent them from entering in the house of Allah.
It's like, he is saying,
I mean, Who are you, people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) to prevent, the people from coming into Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)?
And then in another narration, he said;
اَبَى اللهُ اَنْ تَحُجَّ لَخَمْ وَجُدَام وكِنْده َوَحِمْيَرْ وَيُمْنَعْ مِنْهَا اِبْنَ عَبْدَالْمُطُلِبْ
Allah will not allow Lakham(لَخَم), and Judaam(جُذَام), and Himyar(حِمْيَر), and Kindaa(كِنْدَةْ) to come and visit the house of Allah,
while the son of Abdul-Muttalib(عبدالمطلب) himself is prevented.
These four tribes he mentioned belong to the Yemeni branch of the Arabs
Al-Qahtaniyien(ألقحطانيين), that’s one thing
and the second is that they live in the furthest parts of Arabia.
Lakham(لَخَم), and Judaam(جُذَام) they live to the extreme north of Arabia in Ash-Sham(ألشام)
and then Kindaa(كِنْدَةْ) and Himyar(حِمْيَر) to the extreme south, in the southern parts of Yemen
and he is telling them;
These tribes are allowed to come and visit the house of Allah,
while the son of Abdul-Muttalib(عبدالمطلب), who are from the people of Adnan(عدنان), the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and he is from Makkah itself.
You prevent him and he was very angry
and the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) told him:
Just sit down, you are a Bedouin without any sense.
Al-Hullais(اَلْحُلَيْس) was very angry with that and said;
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) it wasn't for this, that we are allied with you and have a pact with you
shall someone who has come to venerate Allah's house, be barred from it
by Him who holds the soul of Al-Hullais(اَلْحُلَيْس)
either you allow Muhammad(محمد) to do what he has come for
or I will mobilize the Al-Ahabeesh(اَلْاَحَابِيْش) to the last man of them.
He threaten them with war and then the people Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) have calmed him down and said;
Keep silent and leave us alone, until we get for ourselves, what we want.
They're just trying to save face.
All of the envoys were a failure.
Then Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَةبن مسعود), he came to them and said to the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
اَلَسْتُم بِالْوَالِدْ واَلَسْتٌ بِالْوَلَدْ
Aren't you my parents
or aren't you the ones, who have given birth to me and I'm your son,
Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَةبن مسعود), he is from the tribe Thaqeef(ثقيف), who come from At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف).
But his mother was from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and he was one of the great men of Arabia.
In fact, he was one of the suggested names when the Mushrikeen(مشركين) said;
لَوْلَا نُزِّلَ هَٰذَا الْقُرْآنُ عَلَىٰ رَجُلٍ مِنَ الْقَرْيَتَيْنِ عَظِيمٍ۝
Why wasn't this book revealed on one of the great men of the two towns.
They were referring to Makkah and At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف)
So, the Mushrikeen(مشركين) were saying;
Why did Allah chose Muhammad(محمد), why didn't He chose Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود)?
So he was an important figure.
He came to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and he saw that all of this wasn't making sense.
So, he told them; I'm your son.
Do you want me to go and see this man? They said: Yes.
But then I told them;
I have seen all of the insults you have poured on the heads of the people who went as envoys for you.
I mean, whenever one would come back,
whether it is a Al-Hullais(اَلْحُلَيْس) or Budail Bin Warqaa(بديل بن ورقاء), they would insult them
they send them and then they insult them, when they come back
because they come back with an answer different than, what they want to hear.
So, Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) doesn't want the same thing to happen to them.
They said: We trust you and go and speak to him.
So, Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود), he went to Muhammadﷺ and he said;
Hey, now Muhammad(محمد), haven't you considered that you are ruining, your own people?
Have you have heard of any Arab who ruined his people before yourself?
And if that does not happen, I swear, I do not see faces here.
I just see a hodgepodge of people who are quite capable of fleeing and abandoning you.
Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) is mentioning to Rasool Allah ﷺ the two options that he sees;
The first option, is that you win by ruining your own people
then he told him, have you ever seen an Arab man who ruined his own tribe.
This is a tribal society, the tribe is everything
and the way Urwa(عُروة) sees it is that Muhammadﷺ is invading his own people.
And this is unacceptable.
And we haven't heard of anyone who has done such a thing before you.
I mean, he's trying to tell him;
This is a disgrace and this is a shameful thing to do, so don't do it.
And the other option is that you will be defeated.
And he sees this as a likely option because he said;
فَاِنِيْ اَرَاَءْ اَوْبَاشًا
And in another narration;
اَشْوَابًا مِنَّ النَاسْ يُوْشِك اَنْ يَّفِرُّوْ وَيَدَعُوْكْ
I see a hodgepodge of people.
What he is referring to is that, the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم are from different tribes.
They belong to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), they belong to Al-Aos(ألأوس), Al-Khazraj(اَلْخَزرَج), Aslam(اَسْلَم), Ghifaar(غِفَار).
And for some of these tribes like, Aslam(اَسْلَم) and Ghifaar(غِفَار)
they were seen by, by people like Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) as being second class tribes.
I mean, you have the major tribes of the Thaqeef(ثقيف) and Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and then you have these smaller tribes like Aslam(اَسْلَم) and Ghifaar(غِفَار).
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), the larger tribes were slow in accepting Islam
because of their arrogance and pride
and they felt that Islam will take away their position of prominence.
However, these smaller tribes were more willing to listen to the truth
because these barriers were not ahead of them.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ says in Hadith(حديث)
that these tribes are better than Tamim(تميم) and Ghatafaan(غطفان) and Asad(أسد)
you know these big tribes, who people look up to.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
On the Day of Judgment these smaller tribes like Mazeena(مَزِيْنَة) and Juhaynah(جهينة) and Aslam(اسلم) and Ghaffar(غفار)
are heavier on the scale on the Day of Judgment then Tamim(تميم) and Asad(أسد) and Ghatafaan(غطافان) and their likes.
But the Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) was viewing things from the tribal Jahilliyah(جاهلية) view
and he said: What I see is a hodgepodge, a mob of people
that when things get serious, when the rubber hits the road, they're going to leave you alone
they're going to flee and leave you alone.
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) when he heard that, he saw this as a great insult that would not go unnoticed.
So, he told him: Go and suck on Laat(لات)'s clitoris, would we flee and abandon him.?
This was a big insult.
The Arabs used to insult each other, this was a curse among them,
they would say suck on your mother's clitoris,
excuse me for using these words,
but this is knowledge that is mentioned in the books and
لَا اَحْيَآء فِيْ الدِّيْنْ
There is no shame in religion,
we're just narrating what is mentioned in the books of Seerah(سيرة).
So, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) changed it here and replaced mother with Al-Laat(ألات)
and Al-Laat(ألات) was the major god of the people of the Thaqeef(ثقيف).
So, it was a great insult on Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) to tell him this.
Urwa(عُرْوَة) he stared at Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and told him;
If it wasn't because of your favor towards me,
I would have responded back but, I will stay quiet and by this I have paid you back your favor.
Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) was referring to the fact that once he was responsible for paying blood money
and Blood Money is 100 camels.
So, he called people, his friends to help him out.
And people will help him out with one camel, two camels, three camels, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) helped him out with 10.
This is in the time of Jahilliyah(جاهلية).
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was a very generous man.
And the insult was so great that Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَةبن مسعود) saw that
he has paid back Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) for his favor of giving him 10 camels
by just remaining silent and not responding back to him
because this was a big curse to Al-Laat(ألات)
but Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) his temper could not handle such a comment by Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَةبن مسعود)
to say that the Muslims are going to flee and leave Rasool Allah ﷺ alone.
Brothers and Sisters,
what kind of impression does the actions of the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم give the Kuffar(كفار),
when they see their solidarity, and they see their strength
and they see their willingness, to sacrifice for Rasool Allah ﷺ.
No watered down message, no weakness, when it comes to the defense of Rasool Allah ﷺ
we're gonna fight for him and we're never going to leave him alone.
And then Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) when he would speak to Rasool Allah ﷺ
he would extend his hand to hold his beard
and this was something that people would do in those days when they would talk with each other.
It was something acceptable but here Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) is talking with who?
He is talking with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, whenever he would extend his hand
Al-Mugheerah Bin Sho'ba(ألمغيره بن شعبة) who was standing next to Rasool Allah ﷺ to guard him,
while Rasool Allah ﷺ sitting down
and Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة) had his sword in his hand,
he would strike the hand of Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) with the handle of his sword and would tell him;
Keep your hand away from Rasool Allah ﷺ
otherwise, it's not going to return back to you.
I'm going to cut it off.
Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة) was covered in armor from head to toe
and only his eyes could be seen.
So, Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) did not know, who this man was?
So, he told Rasool Allah ﷺ, in one narration
مَا اَفَضكَ وَاَغْلَظَكْ
How rough and rude you are?
And in another narration, he told Rasool Allah ﷺ;
I don't think there's any man more wicked than this man in your army.
Who is he?
Rasool Allah ﷺ smiled and said: This is your nephew Al-Mugheerah Bin Sho'ba(ألمغيره بن شعبة).
Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة) was the nephew of Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود),
what a surprise it would be to Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) to see
that the man who was roughest with him, was his own nephew
and then Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) said: Oh You wicked man, or you man of betrayal;
Have I not just washed away your betrayal yesterday?
What Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) is referring to here,
Al-Mugheerah Bin Sho'ba(ألمغيره بن شعبة) in the time of Jahilliyah(جاهليه) he traveled with 13 Mushrikeen(مُشركين)
and he killed them all stole their money and then ran away to Madina to become Muslim.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told him: I will accept Islam from you but, I will not accept this money.
Because there was trust among these travelers and he betrayed them and took their money.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ said: I want nothing to do with this money.
Rasool Ullah did not paid back to the Mushrikeen(مُشركين), he did not apologize to the Mushrikeen(مُشركين)
but in the same time he refused to accept it
because the way it was taken wasn't right.
Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) was the one, who had to pay it
being the relative of Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة).
And he also had to pay the blood money for all of these men whom Al-Mugheerah Bin Sho'ba(ألمغيره بن شعبة) killed.
So, he's telling Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة),
I just took care of your betrayal and this is how you treat me.
So, you can see brothers and sisters how Islam changed the hearts of these men
and how their love of Rasool Allah ﷺ, they would put it ahead of any personal needs or personal relations,
you know, because Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة) here was helped by his uncle
and at least he should have felt gratitude for that
but his love of Rasool Allah ﷺ, was so great,
that he dealt with Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) in such a manner
because he saw him as being disrespectful with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And I see the statement of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and the action of Al-Mugheera(اَلْمُغِيْرَة) as amazing examples
of how the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم loved Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And sometimes you might not appreciate this, brothers and sisters
until, you put yourself in their shoes,
until you start to think the way, they were thinking
and to put yourself in those circumstances and to see how difficult it would be to act in such a way
unless you have a very deep and sincere love of Rasool Ullah صلواة الله وسلام عليه.
Ibn-e-Hajar(اِبْنِ حَجَر) he comments on the statement of Urwa(عُرْوَةْ)
when he said, that you have two options,
one is to fight your people and defeat them and you would ruin your people then
or your followers would leave you alone and then you would be taken as prisoner.
Ibn-e-Hajar(اِبْنِ حَجَر) says;
وَالْحَاصِلْ اَنَّ عُرْوَةْ رَدَّدَ الْاَمْرَ بَيْنَ شَّيئيْنْ غَيْرَ مسْتَحْسَنَيْنَ عَادَةً
وَهُوَ هَلَاكُ قَوْمِهِ اِنْ غَلَبْ
وَذھابُ اَصْحَابِهِ اِنْ غُلِبْ
لَكِنْ كُلٌ مِّنَّ الْأمرَيْنْ مُسْتَحْسَنٌ شَرْعًا كَمَا قَالَ تعَالَى
قُلْ هَلْ تَرَبَّصُونَ بِنَا إِلَّا إِحْدَى الْحُسْنَيَيْنِ ۖ
Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) he saw the two options as being disliked because of the norms,
the first is the defeat of his people, if he wins
and the fleeing away of his companions if he loses.
However, both of these options are praised Shar'an(شَرْعاً) in Islam.
Islam changes the way, we look at things.
Our norms, our traditions our view changes because of Islam.
So, Ibn-e-Hajar(اِبْنِ حَجَر) is saying,
that if Rasool Allah ﷺ defeated his people, that is something, that is praised in Shar'iah(شرية)
even though, it is his own tribe because it is  Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله).
And if Rasool Allah ﷺ loses, than it is something that is also praiseworthy because it is Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله)
and Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
قُلْ هَلْ تَرَبَّصُونَ بِنَا إِلَّا إِحْدَى الْحُسْنَيَيْنِ ۖ
Allah is telling the Muslims to tell the disbelievers that;
What are you waiting for, to happen to us?
Both are good for us, if we win, or we lose.
Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَةبن مسعود) had an experience of a lifetime.
He went back to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), and what did he say? He said:
Well, I have gone into kings
I had audiences with cesar, Khasro(خُسْرَو) and the Nagis,
and I swear by a Allah
I've never seen the subjects of any King venerate him
the way, Muhammad(محمد)'s people venerate him.
I swear, if he spits, the phelgem always falls into the palm of one of them,
and he would then rub it on to his face or skin.
If he gives them a command, they hurry to carry it out.
If he speaks, they lower their voices in his presence
and they never look directly at him, out of their veneration for him
he has made you an offer, so accept it.
And according to Az-zohri(ألزهري), he said;
I've seen a people, who would never abandon him for any reason.
So, draw your own conclusions.
He came with some ideas, but they were changed
when he saw the reality of the situation in front of his eyes.
When Rasool Ullah would make Wudho'o(وضؤ),
the Sahabah(صحابه) would rush to pick up the droplets of water that would fall down from Rasool Allah ﷺ
and, they would rub it on their skin to get the blessing from Rasool Allah ﷺ.
If a hair falls down, they would take it and they would hide it.
If he would spits, they would take that and Rub it onto themselves.
They saw that everything that had to do with Rasool Allah ﷺ
had the blessings of Rasool Allah ﷺ in it.
This was their respect and love for Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Urwa Bin Masood(عُروَة بن مسعود) is seasoned man, this leader from among his society
the man who has traveled the world and met with the kings
and has met with the greatest kings of the time Qaesar(قيصر) and Kisraa(كِسرى) and An-Najjashi(اَلنَّجَّاشي).
He said: I have never seen something like what I saw in Hudaybiyyah(حديبية).
He was amazed, he was surprised, later on, he would become Muslim.
He was surprised by what he saw.
See brothers or sisters; This is the living example of Da'wah(دعوة)
not the Da'wah(دعوة) of words But the Da'wah(دعوة) of actions.
We need Da'wah(دعوة) of words, but we need Da'wah(دعوة) of actions to confirm it.
Urwa(عُرْوَةْ) has heard the Da'wah(دعوة) of words but now, he saw it with his own eyes.
He saw the embodiment of the Da'wah(دعوة) of the Islam, in front of his eyes.
He told the people of Quraish(قريش), Muhammadﷺ has given you an offer accept it.
There's no way, you could defeat these people.
I don't see any hope for you, he has given you an offer take it.
Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was still in Makkah
and a rumor spread, its time of war, so it's time of rumors.
A rumor spread that he has been killed.
Rasool Allah ﷺ headed towards the campground of Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار),
every clan had its own camping ground.
Umm Ammarah رضي الله عنها, this woman from among Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار).
She said: I saw Rasool Allah ﷺ heading towards our tents.
So, I thought that he needed something
he came and sat down and said;
اِنَّ الله اَمَرَنِيْ بالْبَيْعَهْ
Allah has commanded me to take the pledge from the Muslims
and he asked first man to give him Bay'ah(بيعة)
and then the Muslim started rushing to give him Bay'ah(بيعة).
What was the Bay'ah(بيعة) for, what were the terms of the Bay'ah(بيعة)?
In one narration, to die, we pledge to die,
the other narration, we pledge not to flee from battle
and the third narration,
نُبَايِعُكَ عَلَى مَا فِيْ نَفْسِكْ
We pledge to you, according to what is in your heart.
And this last narration is amazing that the Sahabah(صحابه) are willing to pledge,
whatever is in the heart of Rasool Allah ﷺ we'll pledge to it.
Even if, I don't know
and in fact one can take from these three narrations
that the Sahabah(صحابه) maybe Allah-Ho-Alam(الله اعلم), this could be derived from this.
They weren't sure exactly, what the pledge for
but they were still pledging because whatever Rasool Allah ﷺ would ask from them, they would do.
Also we can see that the meaning is similar between
الموت و ان لا نفر
To die and not to flee from battle.
This was the Bay'ah(بيعة) of Ar-Ridhwaan(الرضوان)
is called the Bay'ah(بيعة) of the pleasure of Allah.
Allah was pleased with the Muslims after this Bay'ah(بيعة).
Why did they give the Bay'ah(بيعة)?
It is because of the rumor that Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) has been killed.
Now, before we proceed, few things regarding this Bay'ah(بيعة);
The Bay'ah(بيعة) was done in the camp of Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار).
So, who are Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار)?
Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار) belongs the tribe of Al-Khazraj(ألخزرج)
and they are the maternal uncles of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
If you remember, if you go back to the Makkah period, we talked about that.
And they were like the close associates and private soldiers of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ made Hijrah(هجرة) to Madina
he first settled with Bannu Amr Bin Auf(بنو عمرو بن عوف) who are on the outskirts of Madina
and this is where he built the Masjid(مسجد) of Quba'a(قباء).
But he went to Madina, where did he stay.?
He stayed with Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار)
and the men of Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار) were surrounding Rasool Allah ﷺ carrying their swords.
They were the private soldiers of Rasool Allah ﷺ
and now he came to them to take the Bay'ah(بيعة) in their own camp.
Umm-e-Ammarah(امّ عَمَّارَةْ) said: My husband held out his sword in his hand, because now this is Bay'ah(بيعة) to die.
So, Umm-e-Ammarah(امّ عَمَّارَةْ) said: I pulled a pole that was holding the tent.
I pulled it out and I held it in one hand and then I stuck a dagger in my waist belt
and I was ready to fight, if anybody would come to me
I will stab him, with the dagger and beat him, with the pole.
This was the preparation of Umm-e-Ammarah رضي الله عنها.
Even though, they were just taking the Bay'ah(بيعة) at that moment
But she wanted to be ready to fight and defend Rasool Allah ﷺ.
This is how, even the women of the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم were
and because she saw herself as belonging to Bannu Najjar(بنونجَّار), the fighters of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
She has to take part in that and she has to be part of this fighting force.
So, she prepared herself to fight and die for Rasool Allah ﷺ,
a position that many men, strong men today are refusing to take.
And then the other thing regarding the Bay'ah(بيعة) of Ar-Ridhwaan(ألرضوان),
is the Bay'ah(بيعة) of Salamah Ibn Aqwa رضي الله عنه.
We've been talking about Salamah(سلمة) a lot lately.
Salamah(سلمة), Rasool Allah ﷺ called him to come and give Bay'ah(بيعة), so he gave Bay'ah(بيعة).
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ saw that he doesn't have any protection, any armor, so he gave him Darqah(درقاه) or Juhfa(جهفه)
and this is a very small shield, it's like size of a Frisbee
and he gave it to him and then Salamah(سلمة) left.
And he met with his uncle and his uncle didn't have any armor.
So, he gave him this shield.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ saw Salamah(سلمة) and told him come and give Bay'ah(بيعة).
Salamah(سلمة) said: I have already given my Bay'ah(بيعة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Give it again.
So, Salamah(سلمة) gave his Bay'ah(بيعة) second time
and then Rasool Allah ﷺ told him: Where is the shield that I gave you?
He said: I gave it to my Uncle.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
مَثَلُكَ كَمَثَلِ الْقَائِلْ اَبْغِنِيْ حَبِيْبًا هُوَ اَحَبَّ اِلَيَّ مِنْ نَّفْسِيْ
The example of you is like the one who said;
O Allah give me somebody, whom I love more than myself.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ saw Salamah(سلمه) a third time and told him; Come and give me Bay'ah(بيعة)
He said: O Rasool Ullah I have already done so.
He said: Give it again.
So, Salamah(سلمه) has given his Bay'ah(بيعة) three times.
He has put his hand, in the hand of Rasool Allah ﷺ for three times
to pledge that you would die for him.
And the third thing to mention regarding Bay'at-Ur-Ridhwan(بيعت الرضوان),
Ar-Rawafidh(الروافض), the Shia(شيعة), they say that Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) has not attended the Battle of Badr(بدر)
and he has not given Bay'ah(بيعة) of Ar-Ridhwan(الرضوان).
Now, we have already, I think talked about, why he didn't attend the Battle of Badr(بدر).
It is because Rasool Allah ﷺ told him not to attend it and to stay behind with his wife
the daughter of Rasool Allah ﷺ, who was on her deathbed.
So, now why did the Uthman(عثمان) not give Bay'ah(بيعة)
and Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), this is such a foolish thing to say about Uthman(عثمان).
I mean, the whole Bay'ah(بيعة) was for the sake of Uthman(عثمان).
That's one thing.
The second thing is that he did give his Bay'ah(بيعة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ put one of his hands in the other hand
and said: This is the Bay'ah(بيعة) for Uthman(عثمان).
So, Uthman(عثمان) didn't give the Bay'ah(بيعة), with his own hand, but it was even better.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, gave the Bay'ah(بيعة) for him, with his own hand.
The blessed hand of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Allahعزوجل says:
اِنَّ أَرْسَلْنَاكَ شَاهِدًا وَمُبَشِّرًا وَنَذِيرًاَ۝
We have truly sent thee, as a witness
as a bringer of glad tidings, as a Warner.
لِتُؤْمِنُوا بِاللَّهِ وَرَسُولِهِ وَتُعَزِّرُوهُ وَتُوَقِّرُوهُ وَتُسَبِّحُوهُ
وَتُسَبِّحُوهُ بُكْرَةً وَأَصِيلًاَ۝
In order that you, O men may believe in Allah and His messenger
that you may assist and honor Him and celebrate His praises morning and evening.
الَّذِينَ يُبَايِعُونَكَ إِنَّمَا يُبَايِعُونَ اللَّهَ يَدُ اللَّهِ فَوْقَ أَيْدِيهِمْ ۚ
فَمَنْ نَكَثَ فَإِنَّمَا يَنْكُثُ عَلَىٰ نَفْسِهِ
وَمَنْ أَوْفَىٰ بِمَا عَاهَدَ عَلَيْهُ اللَّهَ فَسَيُؤْتِيهِ أَجْرًا عَظِيمًا۝
Verily, those who plight their fealty to thee
do no less than plight their fealty to Allah
the hand of Allah is over their hands
then anyone who violates his oath, does so to the harm of his own soul.
And anyone who fulfills what he has covenanted with Allah
Allah will soon grant him a great reward.
These Ayaat(آيات) were revealed that we talk about the Bay'ah(بيعة) of Ar-Ridhwan(ألرضوان).
لَقَدْ رَضِيَ اللَّهُ عَنِ الْمُؤْمِنِينَ إِذْ يُبَايِعُونَكَ تَحْتَ الشَّجَرَةِ
Allahسبحانه وتعالى says that the Allah is pleased with the believers
إِذْ يُبَايِعُونَكَ تَحْتَ الشَّجَرَةِ
The ones, who have pledged their allegiance to you under the tree.
Ibn Abbas(إبن عباس) says about this Ayah(آية).
وَتُعَزِّرُوهُ اَنْ تُقَاتِلُوْبَيْنَ يَدَيْهِ بِسَّيْفْ
Wa-Tuaziroohoo(وَتُعَزِّرُوهُ ), when the Ayah(آية) says, you give support to Rasool Allah ﷺ
Ibn Abbas(إبن عباس) and Ikrimah(عكرمه) said: That you fight ahead of him with your swords
you fight in front of him, with your swords.
That is how the loyalty and the love of Rasool Allah ﷺ is practiced.
This is the Bay'ah(بيعة) of Ar-Ridhwan(الرضوان)
لَقَدْ رَضِيَ اللَّهُ عَنِ الْمُؤْمِنِينَ إِذْ يُبَايِعُونَكَ تَحْتَ الشَّجَرَةِ
Allah is pleased with the believers, who pledged their allegiance to you, under the tree.
This Bay'ah(بيعة),
later on, it was discovered that Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was not killed and it was a false rumor.
But this was only a reason for this amazing event
of pledging to die for the sake of Rasool Allah ﷺ, for the sake of protecting Islam.
This event must have caused great terror in the hearts of the people of Quraish(قريش)
to hear or to see that the Muslims have pledged to die, to the last man,
to fight to the last man, for the sake of defending their religion.
And this was an event witness by the heavens
and the Allahعَزّوجَلّ revealed the Ayaat(آيات) talking about this
and when the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم finished, their Bay'ah(بيعة),
Rasool Allah ﷺ told them.
اَنْتُمْ خِيَّارُ اَهْلِ اَرْضْ
You are the best people, on the face of the earth.
And in another Hadith(حديث) it says,
all of the people who have pledged their allegiance to Rasool Allah ﷺ are forgiven
their sins are forgiven, for them.
اِلَّا صَاحِبُ الْجَمَلْ اَلاحْمَرْ
Except for the owner of the red camel
and this was Al-Jadd Bin Qais(ألجد بن قيس) who did not pledge, his allegiance to Rasool Allah ﷺ
and one of the companion said: I saw him glued to the side of his camel
hiding away from Rasool Allah ﷺ, so that he would not giving him Bay'ah(بيعة).
And when we say that the classes of the different levels and the classes of Sahabah(صحابه).
We say that they the best are the 10 who are given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة)
and then following them are the people of Al-Badr(البدر)
and then following them or the people of Bay'at-Ur-Ridhwan(بيعت الرضوان).
These are the best of humanity.
This is the Bay'ah(بيعة) of Ar-Ridhwan( الرضوان).
Where the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم came to Rasool Allah ﷺ
and offered to give up their lives for the sake of defending, the religion of Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
Now, we go back to the reason, the reason was Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان).
So, this shows you that the Muslims were willing to fight and die for the sake of one man.
One of their men and this shows us how the Ummah(امة).
كَالْبُنْيَانَ الْمَرْصُوْصْ
This is how the Ummah(امة) should be, like one body
when part of the body feels the pain, than the entire body feels that pain and feels the fever.
So, the entire Muslim force a 1400 men, stood up together for the sake of one man
and that's Uthman Ibn Affan رضي الله عنه.
In-Sha-Allah-Ho-Ta'ala(اِنْشاءالله تعالى), we'll carry on with the rest of the story of Al-Hudaybiyya(الحديبية),
in our following session.
وَصَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرًا
واَلسَّلَامُ عَلَيْكُمْ وَرَحْمةُ الله وَبَرَكَاتُه